## **PRAVEEN SETTIPALLI**

praveen\_settipalli@mba.berkeley.edu | (408) 256-1676 | Fremont CA 94539

### SUMMARY

Product leader with 9+ years of experience in product management and web-application development across e-commerce, digital marketing technology and SaaS with a passion for building customer-centric technology products and a track record of delivering award-winning innovations across digital platforms.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Attune Inc. 02/2015 - current

### **Head of Product & Customer Success**

Attune is a Google Ventures backed startup that provides Dynamic Merchandising as a Service for incremental revenue lift and merchandising cost reductions by improving the product discovery experience.

- As the first pre-revenue product hire, lead product vision, roadmap and execution, supported sales pipeline with content marketing, and lead project execution of the product roadmap.
- Built relationships at every level (C-Level stakeholders through PMs and Tech Leads) at E-commerce retailers, managed the project cycle of identifying the right algorithms, use cases and technology stack for the most efficient integration of Attune platform leading to 10X increase in annual revenue.

### Williams Sonoma Inc.

### **Group Product Manager, Global E-commerce**

03/2014 - 01/2015

- Hand picked by and reported to the VP of Global IT to lead e-commerce and digital marketing product management for new global markets. Managed the Launch of websites for Australia, UK and Mexico.
- Created and executed product road map for top of the funnel marketing technology projects (PLAs, affiliate marketing feeds, CRM/email capture etc.) to improve customer acquisition, product discovery experience, and checkout flow optimization to reduce cart abandonment.
- Established Agile methodology for the offshore dev org and successfully delivered bi-weekly sprints with teams across US, Uruguay, Mexico, Australia and India.

### Senior Product Manager, E-commerce Content Management

02/2012 - 02/2014

- Lead cross-functional teams from concept to launch for multiple E-commerce web-technology projects for seven brands that resulted in double digit growth on the \$1.6 Billion annual E-commerce revenue.
- Performed competitive audit, developed product roadmap, lead requirement documentation process and collaborated with IT and UX teams to finalize implementation strategy on the Adobe AEM platform and define success KPIs and measure them using Adobe Omniture.
- As the product owner in an agile software development environment, managed and prioritized the product backlog for projects with annual budgets of \$2 to \$4 Million USD and doubled team velocity.
- Winner of the *Catch the Spirit* award for 2012 Q3 for exceptional performance within a business unit, awarded to 12 among 26,000 global associates.

### **Technical Lead, E-commerce Content Management**

11/2010 – 02/2012

- Developed the technical strategy and architecture for web content management for 300K SKUs across
   7 brands, providing agility for merchandising teams. Developed proof of concept, reviewed code and mentored a development team working on the Java Enterprise technology stack on a CQ5 platform.
- As the technical owner for the platform, managed a four people production support team, defined SLAs and lead weekly meetings to track progress. Reduced peak retail season IT production issues by 50%.

#### **Dew Software Inc.**

IT Consultant, Sr. IT Consultant, Technical Program Manager

06/2006 - 11/2010

## **PRAVEEN SETTIPALLI**

praveen\_settipalli@mba.berkeley.edu | (408) 256-1676 | Fremont CA 94539

Client: Wells Fargo & Company, San Francisco CA.

- Led an IT consultant team on various Wachovia—Wells Fargo merger projects for a customer facing CEO portal web application with 2 million active customers.
- Created functional specification documents and low-level design/architecture documents using UML and Visio. Primary escalation for production support activities during post deployment phase.
- Promoted to Technical Manager and oversaw daily activities of four business systems analysts.

Client: Lexmark International Inc., Lexington KY

- Lead the project delivery efforts for enterprise level data collection applications with millions of data transactions from users in EMEA and Mexico, to enable Lexmark maintain ISO-9000 compliance.
- Worked with client teams to review and finalize requirement documents, wrote code in Java using web frameworks and worked with QA and release management teams to deploy the applications.
- Presented new enterprise technology solutions for improving business process productivity to the senior management and successfully received approval and budget for the initiatives.

### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Business Administration

2016 (expected)

University of California, Berkeley - Walter A. Haas School of Business

- Focus on Marketing, Strategy and Entrepreneurship.
- Vice President Haas Technology Club, Haas Marketing club (2014), VP of Academic Affairs (2015).
- Team Lead and regional finalist for Venture Capital Investment Competition <a href="www.vcic.org">www.vcic.org</a> (2015).

## Master of Science, Electrical Engineering

University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY

2004 - 2006

- Awarded the Kentucky Graduate Scholarship for the entire duration of graduate study.
- Worked full-time as a Research Assistant-Programmer from 08/2005 to 05/2006 and presented the work as Masters thesis to the Graduate School.

## Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Acharya Nagarjuna University, India.

2000 - 2004

First class with distinction, among the top 2% in a graduating class of 600.

#### **ACTIVITIES**

- Entrepreneurship Mentor and Member, Advisory Board BUILD.org: June 2012 April 2013.
- Co-Founder, http://learnspringframework.org: Nov 2008 June 2012
- Participant, Competent Communicator and Leadership series and Sergeant at Arms, ToastBusters A
  San Francisco ToastMasters Club: June 2012 July 2013.